<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jacob Gerard</title>
    <link>https://jagerard.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jacob Gerard</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jagerard.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024 Books</title>
      <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/2024books/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jagerard.com/posts/2024books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past few years I&amp;rsquo;ve set some pretty high reading goals for myself (23 in 2023 and 24 in 2024) and came up short each time. Basically I&amp;rsquo;ve started out each year strong but then got sidetracked by work, learning other things, and pure laziness come late-summer. I still learned a lot and enjoyed the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read each year, but obviously want to push myself to read more. Without going to look up the stats, I think I heard that around 10,000 books come out each year and the average American reads less than 10. I am trying to change this for myself since I appreciate the longer form content and feel that I get a lot more out of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 Yearly Learning Wrap Up</title>
      <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/2022wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jagerard.com/posts/2022wrapup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a short summary of all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for the past&#xA;year. It was a packed schedule for all aspects of my life, and taking time at&#xA;the end of the day to sit down and learn something new wasn&amp;rsquo;t always the top&#xA;priority. But I was able to squeeze in a few useful topics that have been fun&#xA;in my time off work. Most of the coding and technology skills were used to&#xA;build out my home website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes - China: A History</title>
      <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/china/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jagerard.com/posts/china/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;by-john-keay&#34;&gt;By John Keay&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Chinese have had an extremely well detailed history due to their fantastic&#xA;record keeping. Their civilization has been extremely successful, relatively&#xA;continuous, and greatly influential around the world. They seem to specialize&#xA;in taking ideas from all over and improving on them for personal gain. The&#xA;current ruling power of the CCP has a much different take on Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Mandate&#xA;to rule, but they are still interested in how history can be twisted to justify&#xA;current foreign policy positions. I learned a lot about the geography and why&#xA;their society has advanced differently than Western powers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes - Genghis Khan and the Making of the Modern World</title>
      <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/genghis-khan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jagerard.com/posts/genghis-khan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;by-jack-weatherford&#34;&gt;By Jack Weatherford&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mongols had an enormous impact on the world around them. They proved that a&#xA;Steppe people could conquer better due to their speed on the battlefield. They&#xA;also took skills from all areas of their empire to expand capabilities,&#xA;commerce, and improve the lives of all their subjects. They fell prey to&#xA;internal rivalries and losing their military ways after a few generations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;actionable-notes&#34;&gt;Actionable Notes&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Always learn from adversaries and do not be afraid to try new tactics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Controlling propaganda and the narrative around a goal is just as important&#xA;as the tactics used to achieve the goal itself.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do not allow enemies a chance to regroup and learn from an initial assault.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;good-quotes&#34;&gt;Good Quotes&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whether measured by the total number of people defeated, the sum of the&#xA;countries annexed, or by the total area occupied, Genghis Khan conquered more&#xA;than twice as much as any other man in history.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In order to cut through traditional rivalries and feuds in Athens,&#xA;Cleisthenes abolished the tribes and reassigned everyone to ten units of ten,&#xA;thereby transforming a tribal city into a city-state that grew into the&#xA;strongest military, commercial, artistic, and intellectual power along the&#xA;eastern shore of the Mediterranean Sea. Virtually the same reform would&#xA;produce even more astonishing results for the Mongols on the steppes of Inner&#xA;Asia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The postal service ranked alongside the military in importance for the&#xA;Mongols, and individual Mongols were allowed to serve in it in lieu of&#xA;regular military service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In contrast to the massive infantry armies that moved slowly and fought along&#xA;a particular front or on a specific battlefield, the Mongols practiced&#xA;warfare across the entire territory, and the ensuing turmoil and confusion&#xA;allowed the Mongols to employ clever trickery of all sorts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You may conquer an army with superior tactics and men, but you can conquer a&#xA;nation only by conquering the hearts of the people.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mongke recognized the dangers incurred by earlier administrations that issued&#xA;paper money and debt on an ad hoc basis, and in 1253 he created a Department&#xA;of Monetary Affairs to control and standardize the issuance of paper money.&#xA;The superintendent of the agency centralized control to prevent the overissue&#xA;of paper money and the erosion of its value through inflation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Supposedly, because of the importance of narcotics for the Ismailis, the&#xA;people around them called them hashshashin, meaning “the hashish users.” Over&#xA;time, this name became modified into the word assassin. Whether the killers&#xA;had actually used hashish to inspire them or not, the name spread into many&#xA;languages as the word for the murderer of high officials.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Mongol army had accomplished in a mere two years what the European&#xA;Crusaders from the West and the Seljuk Turks from the East had failed to do&#xA;in two centuries of sustained effort. They had conquered the heart of the&#xA;Arab world. No other non-Muslim troops would conquer Baghdad or Iraq again&#xA;until the arrival of the American and British forces in 2003.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The cities of the Khwarizm empire had been a particularly important center&#xA;for mathematic scholarship; the word algorithm was derived from al Khwarizm.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;General literacy increased during the Mongol dynasty, and the volume of&#xA;literary material grew proportionately.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Mongol armies destroyed the uniqueness of the civilizations around them&#xA;by shattering the protective walls that isolated one civilization from&#xA;another and by knotting the cultures together.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Notes - Napoleon: A Life</title>
      <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/napoleon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jagerard.com/posts/napoleon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;by-andrew-roberts&#34;&gt;By Andrew Roberts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;impressions&#34;&gt;Impressions&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Napoleon was one of the most influential figures in history. He was a general&#xA;who rarely lost battles and did not needlessly start wars (most were declared&#xA;on him). He had a constant desire to be doing work and was extremely well read&#xA;and interested in a multitude of subjects. Many of his actions impacted the&#xA;next century in Europe and led to military formations and administration that&#xA;is still with us today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generic Data Structures in C</title>
      <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/structures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jagerard.com/posts/structures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;idea&#34;&gt;Idea&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a few small programming projects over the past few weeks. C++ and it&amp;rsquo;s object oriented model makes generic data structures a lot simpler, but the syntax and bloat of everything gets a little complex. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been using C for most everything besides small web projects. I decided to build up my own little library of generic data structures so that I can just pull these into any projects moving forward. This should help prevent me from reinventing the wheel every time, but it has been fun to get back to the basics with this. Definitely not optimal solutions (I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss that below), but they hit the gist of what I need.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jagerard.com/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m a computer science graduate interested in cyber security and systems programming. I don’t currently work in a technical role that would be beneficial to getting a job in the cyber field. There is a plan in place for that to change in the next few years, but in the meantime I figured that a blog would give me a platform to showcase my studies, projects, and research. It will also (hopefully) motivate me to keep moving in the right direction during my free time!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jagerard.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jagerard.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;https://jagerard.com/img/portrait.jpg&#34;  alt=&#34;Portrait&#34;  class=&#34;center&#34;  style=&#34;border-radius: 25px; max-width: 75vw;&#34;  /&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a Computer Science graduate from the US Naval Academy interested in systems programming and experimenting with free software projects. In the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve assisted with research on parallelized visualization techniques and graph encryption algorithms. Outside of the computing world, I enjoy playing volleyball and card games with friends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
