<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Jacob Gerard</title>
        <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Jacob Gerard</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -1000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://jagerard.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>2022 Yearly Learning Wrap Up</title>
            <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/2022wrapup/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -1000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jagerard.com/posts/2022wrapup/</guid>
            <description>This is a short summary of all the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for the past year. It was a packed schedule for all aspects of my life, and taking time at the end of the day to sit down and learn something new wasn&amp;rsquo;t always the top priority. But I was able to squeeze in a few useful topics that have been fun in my time off work. Most of the coding and technology skills were used to build out my home website.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a short summary of all the things I&rsquo;ve been working on for the past
year. It was a packed schedule for all aspects of my life, and taking time at
the end of the day to sit down and learn something new wasn&rsquo;t always the top
priority. But I was able to squeeze in a few useful topics that have been fun
in my time off work. Most of the coding and technology skills were used to
build out my home website.</p>
<h2 id="computing">Computing</h2>
<p>For a little over a year I have been internally hosting a Flask website that
takes in expense data and tracks savings progress in Python. This all hooks in
to a SQLite database which I can query or run simple analytics on to track my
financial goals. It started out very basic with Jinja templates that would show
the results of queries, but has since grown to support almost all of my
financial needs.</p>
<p>During the first half of the year I decided to really step it up. I optimized
the back end and made more efficient use of SQL queries. During the late spring
and early summer I learned JavaScript basics and wrote an API layer so that I
could run Asynchronous queries and update the DOM to reflect this. I improved
the overall layout of the site with more refined CSS. Then, towards the end of
the year, I again improved on the layout and fixed all the spaghetti code that
I wrote to manage the single page application sections. I also began to study a
little bit of data science and plotting with matplotlib and used that to write
an awesome year end summary in LaTeX.</p>
<p>These skills sort of moved all over the place, but I basically did a slow build
up from an idea that I had last year. I was tired of trying to track things
across different Excel pages and knew that a database would be a more elegant
solution. I progressively built a web application that could cleanly represent
my data and motivate me to progress quickly to my savings goals. Currently the
site inputs and updates expenses, tracks budgets, retrieves savings and net
worth numbers, and charts out growth. I can filter queries and easily navigate
through the main functions.</p>
<p>On top of that, I can proudly say that I wrote all the front end code for this
website by hand (including the CSS) to eliminate any calls to outside libraries
like Bootstrap. The back end is Python that uses Flask to serve the application
and feeds off business logic that I wrote for a command line version of the
budgeting software. All this is self-hosted on my Fedora desktop and served
through an NGINX web server.</p>
<p>I will continue to build features onto this site throughout 2023. The primary
thing I&rsquo;m missing is a nice way to check on my investment data within the web
app. I think that I will be able to build out a few pages that either track
what I already have at the beginning of each month, or potentially log into the
sites and scrape my investment data into the app. I&rsquo;ll take a break at the
beginning of the year, but will probably hit the ground running on that in
February.</p>
<p>I would love to upload this project to my GitHub page, but due to the sensitive
nature of financial data I have been reluctant to do that for fear that I left
some major identifying information in the code. I will be attempting to go
through and clean my git repo so that this can be made public. There are other
projects that can do this better; but I have learned a lot while implementing
this and it fits my needs nicely.</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve read 13 books and wrote up 3 posts with notes and quotes! I&rsquo;ll link those
here and then post my impressions of a few of the others that I learned a good
deal from. I highly recommend <em>The Psychology of Money</em> by Morgan Housel as I
think everybody can get a lot out of it. Plus its a fairly quick read.</p>
<ol>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> <a href="/posts/napoleon">Napoleon: A Life - Andrew Roberts</a></li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Ender&rsquo;s Game - Orson Scott Card</li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> <a href="/posts/genghis-khan">Genghis Khan and the Making of the Modern World - Jack Weatherford</a></li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Where the Crawdads Sing - Delia Owens</li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Dune - Frank Herbert</li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Verity - Colleen Hoover</li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> <a href="/posts/china">China: A History - John Keay</a></li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Starship Troopers - Robert Heinlein</li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Psychology of Money - Morgan Housel
<ul>
<li>Good stories about how to be more successful in personal finances by
staying the course and recognizing that some people or industries just
get lucky. Long term investing is the surest path to success and you need
to save just for unexpected life events, not necessarily only for big
purchases.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Catch-22 - Joseph Heller</li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Outliers: The Story of Success - Malcolm Gladwell
<ul>
<li>Success is tough to achieve just by hard work alone. Most of the
extremely successful people in the world had very unusual circumstances
that put them in positions to be the best at something right when it was
necessary. There is not much to do to control that. But it also points
out that the people you surround yourself with are very likely to have a
large impact on your standing in the world.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> A Brief History of Time - Stephen Hawking
<ul>
<li>Stunning overview of very complicated math and science in an easily
digestable format. This is an inspiration to start looking into those
tough problems with a new lens about how they all fit together into grand
theories of the universe.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><input checked="" disabled="" type="checkbox"> Thinking Fast and Slow - Daniel Kahneman</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="random">Random</h2>
<p>I have also spent a fair amount of time listening to a few podcasts that
interest me. Sticking with the theme of finances, I love the Rational Reminder
podcast and try to listen to each episode as they come out weekly. I also fit
in a few episodes of Hardcore History by Dan Carlin. They are longer shows, but
packed with tons of information and tell history in a way that you usually
can&rsquo;t get from anywhere else unless you want to read textbooks all day.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve also read the Wall Street Journal (almost daily), Foreign Affairs, The
Economist (in the last quarter of the year), and a few articles from the US
Naval Institute Proceedings. Next year, I am going to cut down on the
newspapers and magazines that I read in order to fit in more books. Aiming for
23 in 2023 after inspiration from the folks at the Rational Reminder podcast.</p>
<h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap Up</h2>
<p>That is basically a summary of my year in learning for 2022. I tried to get up
and learn something new each week. There are lots of little lessons in there
that I learned throughout as well, but not everything merits a comment on this
blog. I plan to keep pushing myself further next year. The one area where I
didn&rsquo;t take much advantage of my time was keeping this site up to date. I will
try to get better with that and may post some smaller articles about simple
topics as how-to references for myself and anybody else who happens to stumble
on these notes. Please feel free to reach out if you have any questions or
recommendations for things that I can take a look at. Always looking for new
knowledge!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Book Notes - China: A History</title>
            <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/china/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jagerard.com/posts/china/</guid>
            <description>By John Keay Impressions The Chinese have had an extremely well detailed history due to their fantastic record keeping. Their civilization has been extremely successful, relatively continuous, and greatly influential around the world. They seem to specialize in taking ideas from all over and improving on them for personal gain. The current ruling power of the CCP has a much different take on Heaven&amp;rsquo;s Mandate to rule, but they are still interested in how history can be twisted to justify current foreign policy positions.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="by-john-keay">By John Keay</h2>
<h3 id="impressions">Impressions</h3>
<p>The Chinese have had an extremely well detailed history due to their fantastic
record keeping. Their civilization has been extremely successful, relatively
continuous, and greatly influential around the world. They seem to specialize
in taking ideas from all over and improving on them for personal gain. The
current ruling power of the CCP has a much different take on Heaven&rsquo;s Mandate
to rule, but they are still interested in how history can be twisted to justify
current foreign policy positions. I learned a lot about the geography and why
their society has advanced differently than Western powers.</p>
<h3 id="actionable-notes">Actionable Notes</h3>
<ol>
<li>Keep detailed records and refer back to them frequently.</li>
<li>Learn the history and influences on other countries&rsquo; culture to have the
greatest impact in foreign policy negotiations.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="quotes">Quotes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Of all the issues involved in the power struggle - territorial, dynastic,
philosophical, and fiscal- perhaps the most surporising was social, in that
dissent swelled from the lowest ranks of society. Resistance to Qin rule
proved to be not just popular but populist&hellip; While nationalists would later
applaud the First Emperor&rsquo;s efforts at unification, and while Maoists would
approve his autocratic efforts in mass mobilisation, orthodox Marxists would
be more gratified by the anti-Qin response and its early evidence of peasant
revolt and class consciousness.</li>
<li>Rome&rsquo;s near-contemporary empire was comparable in size and would last several
centuries. But China&rsquo;s would weather the millenia. Many explanations -
geographical, psychological, even genetic - have been offered for the
contrasting fortunes of the two empiresand for the different political orders
to which they would give rise - fragmentary and increasingly conensual in the
case of Europe&rsquo;s nation-states, unitary and increasingly authoritarian in the
case of China&rsquo;s empire. Explanations that emphasize imperial China&rsquo;s more
effective administrative structure and its more flexible ideology are
certainly not the most exciting. Yet they carry conviction; and both - the
administrative machinery and its ideological lubricant - were honed under the
Han.</li>
<li>The Chang&rsquo;an bureaucracy ground to a halt - as bureaucracies do - when the
supply of paper ran out.</li>
<li>Born in 599, the great Tang Taizong, contructor if not architect of the Tang
empire, belonged to a generation of Asian empire-builders. From the Tsangpo
basin of southern Tibet, Srong-brtsan-sgam-po, his exact contemporary, was
masterminding the first unification of the scattered peoples of Asia&rsquo;s high
plateau to lay the foundations of a formidable Tibetan empire. Across the
Himalayas in the Gangetic plain, Harsha-vardhana of Kanauj was performing a
similar feat in establishing his imperial sway over the Hindu-Buddhist
kingdoms of north India. Simultaneously the Sassanid ruler Chosroes (Khosrau)
II was overrunning the Levant and Asia Minor to recreate a Persian empire the
stretched from Xinjiang to Egypt. And in the far south-west, along the
caravan routes of Arabia, another contemporary took rejection in Mecca as
cause for flight (hegira or hijra) to Medina, where, acknowledged as the
Prophet, he found a following and launched a crescentade that in less than a
centure would obliterate the Sassanids and buffet the frontiers of both India
and China.</li>
<li>For just as war, being notoriously unpredictable, was to be considered a last
resort, so battle was to be offered only when victory was guaranteed. Indeed,
if war represented a failure of diplomacy, then deployment represented a
failure of strategy, and battle a failure of tactics.</li>
<li>[Of the Jin] A dynasty that, for all its faults, had set an example,
substatially followed by both Mongols and Manchus, of how non-Han rule could
be made acceptable to an overwhelmingly Han population had finally proved
itself worthy of the Mandate; extinction with honour had been preferred to
the shame of a mock abdication. The Southern Song, come their turn, would
know what was expected of them.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Book Notes - Genghis Khan and the Making of the Modern World</title>
            <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/genghis-khan/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jagerard.com/posts/genghis-khan/</guid>
            <description>By Jack Weatherford Impressions The Mongols had an enormous impact on the world around them. They proved that a Steppe people could conquer better due to their speed on the battlefield. They also took skills from all areas of their empire to expand capabilities, commerce, and improve the lives of all their subjects. They fell prey to internal rivalries and losing their military ways after a few generations.
Actionable Notes Always learn from adversaries and do not be afraid to try new tactics.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="by-jack-weatherford">By Jack Weatherford</h2>
<h3 id="impressions">Impressions</h3>
<p>The Mongols had an enormous impact on the world around them. They proved that a
Steppe people could conquer better due to their speed on the battlefield. They
also took skills from all areas of their empire to expand capabilities,
commerce, and improve the lives of all their subjects. They fell prey to
internal rivalries and losing their military ways after a few generations.</p>
<h3 id="actionable-notes">Actionable Notes</h3>
<ol>
<li>Always learn from adversaries and do not be afraid to try new tactics.</li>
<li>Controlling propaganda and the narrative around a goal is just as important
as the tactics used to achieve the goal itself.</li>
<li>Do not allow enemies a chance to regroup and learn from an initial assault.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="good-quotes">Good Quotes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Whether measured by the total number of people defeated, the sum of the
countries annexed, or by the total area occupied, Genghis Khan conquered more
than twice as much as any other man in history.</li>
<li>In order to cut through traditional rivalries and feuds in Athens,
Cleisthenes abolished the tribes and reassigned everyone to ten units of ten,
thereby transforming a tribal city into a city-state that grew into the
strongest military, commercial, artistic, and intellectual power along the
eastern shore of the Mediterranean Sea. Virtually the same reform would
produce even more astonishing results for the Mongols on the steppes of Inner
Asia.</li>
<li>The postal service ranked alongside the military in importance for the
Mongols, and individual Mongols were allowed to serve in it in lieu of
regular military service.</li>
<li>In contrast to the massive infantry armies that moved slowly and fought along
a particular front or on a specific battlefield, the Mongols practiced
warfare across the entire territory, and the ensuing turmoil and confusion
allowed the Mongols to employ clever trickery of all sorts.</li>
<li>You may conquer an army with superior tactics and men, but you can conquer a
nation only by conquering the hearts of the people.</li>
<li>Mongke recognized the dangers incurred by earlier administrations that issued
paper money and debt on an ad hoc basis, and in 1253 he created a Department
of Monetary Affairs to control and standardize the issuance of paper money.
The superintendent of the agency centralized control to prevent the overissue
of paper money and the erosion of its value through inflation.</li>
<li>Supposedly, because of the importance of narcotics for the Ismailis, the
people around them called them hashshashin, meaning “the hashish users.” Over
time, this name became modified into the word assassin. Whether the killers
had actually used hashish to inspire them or not, the name spread into many
languages as the word for the murderer of high officials.</li>
<li>The Mongol army had accomplished in a mere two years what the European
Crusaders from the West and the Seljuk Turks from the East had failed to do
in two centuries of sustained effort. They had conquered the heart of the
Arab world. No other non-Muslim troops would conquer Baghdad or Iraq again
until the arrival of the American and British forces in 2003.</li>
<li>The cities of the Khwarizm empire had been a particularly important center
for mathematic scholarship; the word algorithm was derived from al Khwarizm.</li>
<li>General literacy increased during the Mongol dynasty, and the volume of
literary material grew proportionately.</li>
<li>The Mongol armies destroyed the uniqueness of the civilizations around them
by shattering the protective walls that isolated one civilization from
another and by knotting the cultures together.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Book Notes - Napoleon: A Life</title>
            <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/napoleon/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jagerard.com/posts/napoleon/</guid>
            <description>By Andrew Roberts Impressions Napoleon was one of the most influential figures in history. He was a general who rarely lost battles and did not needlessly start wars (most were declared on him). He had a constant desire to be doing work and was extremely well read and interested in a multitude of subjects. Many of his actions impacted the next century in Europe and led to military formations and administration that is still with us today.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="by-andrew-roberts">By Andrew Roberts</h2>
<h3 id="impressions">Impressions</h3>
<p>Napoleon was one of the most influential figures in history. He was a general
who rarely lost battles and did not needlessly start wars (most were declared
on him). He had a constant desire to be doing work and was extremely well read
and interested in a multitude of subjects. Many of his actions impacted the
next century in Europe and led to military formations and administration that
is still with us today.</p>
<h3 id="actionable-notes">Actionable Notes</h3>
<ol>
<li>Read more. Napoleon read all the time and was extremely well-versed in his
ancient history.</li>
<li>Constantly be learning something new.</li>
<li>Do not meddle in other people&rsquo;s love lives.</li>
<li>Do not become too arrogant/stick to guiding principles. He lost later wars
because he could not follow his own military maxims.</li>
<li>Do not blindly trust family or give people limitless opportunities to prove
their worth.</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="good-quotes">Good Quotes</h3>
<ul>
<li>Since the campaign had begun a year earlier, Napoleon had crossed the
Apennines and the Alps, defeated a Sardinian army and no fewer than six
Austrian armies, and killed, wounded or captured 120,000 Austrian soldiers.
<strong>All this he had done before his twenty-eighth birthday.</strong> Eighteen months
earlier he had been an unknown, moody soldier writing essays on suicide; now
he was famous across Europe, having defeated mighty Austria, wrung peace
treaties from the Pope and the kings of Piedmont and Naples, abolished the
medieval dukedom of Modena, and defeated in every conceivable set of military
circumstances most of Austria’s most celebrated generals – Beaulieu, Wurmser,
Provera, Quasdanovich, Alvinczi, Davidovich – and outwitted the Archduke
Charles.</li>
<li>In an unscripted speech to the Conseil in 1806, which he made only because
his education minister, Antoine Fourcroy, hadn’t brought his report to the
meeting, Napoleon was almost poetic about how education was the most
important of all the institutions, since everything depends upon it, the
present and the future. It is essential that the morals and political ideas
of the generation which is now growing up should no longer be dependent on
the news of the day or the circumstances of the moment&hellip; Men already differ
enough in their inclinations, their characters and everything that education
does not give and cannot reform&hellip; Let us have a body of doctrine that
doesn’t vary and a body of teachers that doesn’t die.</li>
<li>Alsatian Jews made up nearly half of France’s Jewish population of 55,000,
and they were blamed for ‘excessive’ usury in that curious inversion whereby
people who borrow money under free contracts in an open market blame those
who lend it to them.</li>
<li>‘Society in the salons is always in a state of hostility against the
government. Everything is criticized and nothing praised.’</li>
<li>He was adamant that his role in international affairs was over. ‘History has
a triumvirate of great men,’ Macnamara stated, ‘Alexander, Caesar, and
Napoleon.’ At this, Napoleon looked steadfastly at him without speaking, and
Macnamara said ‘he thought he saw the Emperor’s eyes moisten.’</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Generic Data Structures in C</title>
            <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/structures/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jagerard.com/posts/structures/</guid>
            <description>Idea I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a few small programming projects over the past few weeks. C++ and it&amp;rsquo;s object oriented model makes generic data structures a lot simpler, but the syntax and bloat of everything gets a little complex. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been using C for most everything besides small web projects. I decided to build up my own little library of generic data structures so that I can just pull these into any projects moving forward.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="idea">Idea</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been working on a few small programming projects over the past few weeks. C++ and it&rsquo;s object oriented model makes generic data structures a lot simpler, but the syntax and bloat of everything gets a little complex. Recently I&rsquo;ve been using C for most everything besides small web projects. I decided to build up my own little library of generic data structures so that I can just pull these into any projects moving forward. This should help prevent me from reinventing the wheel every time, but it has been fun to get back to the basics with this. Definitely not optimal solutions (I&rsquo;ll discuss that below), but they hit the gist of what I need.</p>
<h2 id="implementation">Implementation</h2>
<p>I opted to use void pointers and copy the contents of elements directly into the structure. This keeps the data nearby in most structures so I reduce page faults from following pointers around the heap, but adds a memory copy during the initialization of a new element. I am willing to make that sacrifice since most of my projects will be accessing memory much more often than modifying it. But if I need to do things the other way then I&rsquo;ll make adjustments as necessary.</p>
<p>The other disadvantage of using these void pointers is that it could get confusing if you try to access things without saving function pointers to print or compare elements. I wrote the code so I know that if I just stick to the public functions things should be fine. But trying to make direct accesses to the internals of these structures could cause a lot of problems.</p>
<p>Overall this experience has definitely highlighted the advantage of using a language like C++ for stronger types and operator overloading. But I&rsquo;m happy I gave it a shot and know that it will come in handy moving forward. I will post the more complete set of code on my GitHub, but below is a short example of how I was managing the generics in my structures. I plan on providing a useful and working implementation of Array List, Linked List, Binary Search Tree, AVL Tree, B-Tree, and Hash Table.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-C" data-lang="C"><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#66d9ef">struct</span> alist{
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    <span style="color:#66d9ef">size_t</span> elementsize;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    <span style="color:#66d9ef">size_t</span> maxsize;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    <span style="color:#66d9ef">size_t</span> size;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    <span style="color:#66d9ef">void</span> <span style="color:#f92672">*</span>list;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>};
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#66d9ef">struct</span> alist <span style="color:#f92672">*</span><span style="color:#a6e22e">alist_init</span>(<span style="color:#66d9ef">size_t</span> elementsize, <span style="color:#66d9ef">size_t</span> maxsize){
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    <span style="color:#66d9ef">struct</span> alist <span style="color:#f92672">*</span>list <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">malloc</span>(<span style="color:#66d9ef">sizeof</span>(<span style="color:#f92672">*</span>list));
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    list<span style="color:#f92672">-&gt;</span>elementsize <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> elementsize;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    list<span style="color:#f92672">-&gt;</span>maxsize <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> maxsize;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    list<span style="color:#f92672">-&gt;</span>size <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#ae81ff">0</span>;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    list<span style="color:#f92672">-&gt;</span>list <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">malloc</span>(elementsize <span style="color:#f92672">*</span> maxsize);
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    <span style="color:#66d9ef">if</span>(list<span style="color:#f92672">-&gt;</span>list <span style="color:#f92672">==</span> NULL){
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>        <span style="color:#66d9ef">return</span> NULL;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    }
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    <span style="color:#66d9ef">return</span> list;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>}
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span><span style="color:#66d9ef">void</span> <span style="color:#f92672">*</span><span style="color:#a6e22e">alist_insert</span>(<span style="color:#66d9ef">struct</span> alist <span style="color:#f92672">*</span>list, <span style="color:#66d9ef">unsigned</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">int</span> position, <span style="color:#66d9ef">void</span> <span style="color:#f92672">*</span>valptr){
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    ...
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    <span style="color:#66d9ef">uint8_t</span> <span style="color:#f92672">*</span>array <span style="color:#f92672">=</span> list<span style="color:#f92672">-&gt;</span>list;
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    <span style="color:#a6e22e">memcpy</span>(<span style="color:#f92672">&amp;</span>array[position <span style="color:#f92672">*</span> list<span style="color:#f92672">-&gt;</span>elementsize], valptr, list<span style="color:#f92672">-&gt;</span>elementsize);
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>    ...
</span></span><span style="display:flex;"><span>}
</span></span></code></pre></div>]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Hello World</title>
            <link>https://jagerard.com/posts/hello-world/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jagerard.com/posts/hello-world/</guid>
            <description>I’m a computer science graduate interested in cyber security and systems programming. I don’t currently work in a technical role that would be beneficial to getting a job in the cyber field. There is a plan in place for that to change in the next few years, but in the meantime I figured that a blog would give me a platform to showcase my studies, projects, and research. It will also (hopefully) motivate me to keep moving in the right direction during my free time!</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m a computer science graduate interested in cyber security and systems programming. I don’t currently work in a technical role that would be beneficial to getting a job in the cyber field. There is a plan in place for that to change in the next few years, but in the meantime I figured that a blog would give me a platform to showcase my studies, projects, and research. It will also (hopefully) motivate me to keep moving in the right direction during my free time!</p>
<p>I expect that the majority of my posts here will be short updates on what I’ve been researching, interesting challenges or courses I’ve finished, and comments on current events in the industry. All this comes with the ambitious goal of eventually passing the OSCP. I don’t know if it is possible in the next few years, but setting my sights high will at least put me in a comfortable position for when I transition to a new career field down the road.</p>
<p>If you are interested in any of my posts, have advice for the best ways to move forward, or just want to chat, then feel free to send me an email. I’m looking forward to hopping into the work and hope to share some good bits of information with you soon.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
